<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on CybersecurityOS</title>
    <link>https://cybersecurityos.net/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on CybersecurityOS</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cybersecurityos.net/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Broader Cloud Context: The Missing Piece in CNAPP</title>
      <link>https://cybersecurityos.net/posts/cloud/cnapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cybersecurityos.net/posts/cloud/cnapp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rapid evolution of cloud environments has brought transformative benefits for businesses, but it has also introduced significant security challenges. As organizations increasingly move to cloud-native architectures, traditional security tools and approaches are struggling to keep up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enter the &lt;strong&gt;Cloud-Native Application Protection Platform (CNAPP)&lt;/strong&gt;, an emerging category that promises to streamline and modernize cloud security.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, we’ll dive into the concept of CNAPP, explore the shift towards &lt;strong&gt;agentless security&lt;/strong&gt;, and examine how &lt;strong&gt;workload protection&lt;/strong&gt; plays a crucial role in securing cloud-native applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pylint Power-Up: Automated Code Quality Checks for GitHub Projects</title>
      <link>https://cybersecurityos.net/posts/python/pylint-github-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cybersecurityos.net/posts/python/pylint-github-action/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pylint is a powerful tool for analyzing Python code to ensure it follows coding standards and best practices. Integrating Pylint into your GitHub repository as part of your CI/CD pipeline helps maintain clean, readable, and error-free code. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick guide on how to configure Pylint in GitHub using GitHub Actions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;GitHub Repo Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/d0uble3L/pylint-demo&#34;&gt;d0uble3l. GitHub&lt;/a&gt;*&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;set-up-a-github-action-for-pylint&#34;&gt;Set Up a GitHub Action for Pylint&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Create a .github/workflows directory in the root of your repository if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of AI in DevSecOps: Building Secure Applications Faster</title>
      <link>https://cybersecurityos.net/posts/ai-devsecops/ai-impact-on-devsecops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 23:29:07 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cybersecurityos.net/posts/ai-devsecops/ai-impact-on-devsecops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As artificial intelligence (AI) rapidly advances, its profound implications for these practices offer unprecedented opportunities to further strengthen our security posture and streamline processes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post I will focus on the transformative integration of DevSecOps and how the shift-left philosophy has fundamentally enhanced how organizations approach security throughout the software development lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-devsecops-and-shifting-left&#34;&gt;Understanding DevSecOps and Shifting Left&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DevSecOps integrates security practices within the DevOps process, ensuring that security is a shared responsibility throughout the software development lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vulnerability Management 101: A Beginner&#39;s Guide to Strengthening Your Cybersecurity</title>
      <link>https://cybersecurityos.net/posts/vuln/vulnerability-management-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 23:19:07 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cybersecurityos.net/posts/vuln/vulnerability-management-101/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s digital world, no organization is immune to cyber threats. From small businesses to global enterprises, everyone is a potential target for hackers seeking to exploit vulnerabilities. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a seasoned cybersecurity professional or a curious beginner, understanding &lt;strong&gt;vulnerability management&lt;/strong&gt; is key to safeguarding your systems and data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll break down the basics of vulnerability management, explain why it&amp;rsquo;s important, and provide steps for implementing an effective vulnerability management program.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
